what is an autodidact I've talked about
this a lot there's lots of videos on
this but let's actually do a search for
what it is
what uh whoops if I could type what is
an autodidact now I have my ideas about
what it is but you guys go look it up an
autodidact is a self- toop person who
learns without formal education or
instruction learn the emology I always
can f confuse that with entomology which
is a study of bugs not the same thing
learn the atmology history and examples
of this word from the Miriam Webster
dictionary all right so there's another
good one uh T Ando is a famous autod
doic architect of the 21st century many
successful influential Architects blah
blah blah were
selftaught so I guess I turned that off
but here you go there's there's where
the the the information comes from um
and Auto DCT is more than a self-taught
learner and really the takeaway from
this video is is that an autodidact is
someone who goes the extra length of
time extra mile whatever and rather than
just learning on their own um they make
a plan so the difference between oh I am
an independent learner and an autodidact
is an autodidact has a plan that means
that they have set aside time for
themselves they they've considered what
it is they need to learn they
potentially Ed time back boxing
techniques to focus they they you know
they they have taken on the task of
learning and the why should you become
an autodidact because the entire tech
industry is driven by autodidactic
Engineers these are people who
fundamentally You could argue that you
really can't be a good engineer without
being someone who's constantly
controlling their own learning and when
you go back far enough you start to see
that some of the the early autodidactic
Engineers uh that created you know
scientists in general um there was
nothing there was no other way to learn
the things it's not like you could go
open a book or do an internet search or
go you know go even to somebody else you
couldn't even cross the sea and talk to
a specialist about a thing because it
didn't exist so so you know whe whether
it's you know quantum theory you know
Neils bore or it's like you know you
know it's electricity with Tesla or any
of these people they invented these
things because there was no other way to
learn about them they had to set up so
so
autodidacticism I think that's a word
goes hand inand with um that
scientific
entrepreneurialism uh which yes I do
think that they go together where you're
constant finding a new way uh we talked
about the virtues of it and and you you
go watch that video but they are in sync
with all of this right people want a
thing and they they want their life to
be easier they they they want to fix a
problem that they have and so they set
about the you know the the work of
making a plan to make the thing and to
doing what it takes to get it that is
what it means to be an autod um there is
another way of saying this and I I use
it all the time learn to think like a
hacker and I've talked about that in
another video but autod hackers are just
Engineers Auto they're some of the most
autodidactic people in the world they
they take the idea of a thing and not
only do they say Okay I want to master
that idea but they look at the idea from
different angles it's like think outside
the box if you want to use a cliche you
no they're they're like so far out of
the box they're going to make a new
box I'm going to make a new box here's
my box use my box instead or I'm going
to you know make use it for a they are
naturally autodidactic individuals um
quick little story uh if you if you if
you've ever been with somebody who's not
an so I had somebody that I used to work
with let me let me tell you I'm going to
tell you two stories about people who
are autodidactic and people who are not
okay one of them is my wife and the
other one is somebody who shall not be
named okay and this is why I hate
cubicles so I was I was working uh in a
cubicle at a particular company I will
not say which one
and there was this person um who was
always asking me questions they were
like I mean seriously sometimes they
would even ask hey man what time is it
or hey man what's the weather like I'm
like literally you can Google let me
Google that for you which by the way is
a really funny website I'm not going to
do it now but um so you know they could
they could go about the business of
doing all their own research but they
didn't you know and they had no desire
to do so they were constantly in my
cubicle all the time haunting my cubicle
door going what am I going to do uh how
am I going to get help with this and but
you know when I tell this story I have
to be careful because sometimes being a
responsible it person is owning the fact
that you do not know the answer right
and you need to get help and you need to
go to your learning community your
professional Learning Community which
we'll talk about in another video and
you need to build up that Community to
go to them and say look I this is the
work I have done to try to answer this
myself make sure you do that work first
and the research and here's where what
I'm still missing or maybe you make a
conclusion and then you get it validated
again all of that is going to be
discussed in the personal professional
Learning Network that's a really
important
conversation I don't want to take away
from that so if you know I don't want to
say what Thou shalt not leave your
cubicle and go talk to other people
that's not what I'm saying what I'm
saying is don't be intellectually lazy
and I was going to make it might be
actually that might be the that might be
the thumbnail intellectual laziness I
have no time for intellectual laziness
intellectual laziness are people who are
not dumb they're just lazy and they're
not lazy in a good way they're lazy in
the way that they want somebody else to
do just the thinking for them because
they're just too lazy to do it like
right own tool and do the so an
autodidactic doesn't an autodidactic
person not only does their own research
and leans on their own understanding
first before they go lean on somebody
else uh but you know they they have a
sort of an you know they have sort of an
aversion for the kind of person who's
going to haunt your door and ask you
really stupid things and hey I got this
thing you know and uh if you if you work
in technology for any amount of time
you'll know there are people who have
like less or social skills who will not
put up with that and um so one of the
reasons I want to teach you about this
autodidactic thing is I want to save you
from and this and I'm going to I I have
another story to tell you all on a
positive note but I have another story
to tell you about people who are not
autodidactic people who do not set up
set about to to learn their own to
answer their own problems and and and
you know let alone a plan for how to
learn you know an entire technology or
language or something another place is
in the chat rooms in the chat rooms uh
and I specifically have had experience
with IRC but people who the equivalent
of of that they they go from you know
one cubicle to another they go into an
IRC room that's got a fact about all the
answers and they ask the question anyway
and they get roasted by the people that
are in there and and they really let
them have it and then they're like you
guys suck you guys are all mean why are
we could have just answered the question
why didn't you just answer it instead of
letting me have it you know it could
have it taking 10 minutes and by the way
I'm guilty of this so four years ago in
2020 when I started streaming to Twitch
I have a personal habit with the people
that I mentor of shaming them a little
bit when they ask me a question they
could have answered themselves because I
have no tolerance for intellectual
laziness and frankly smacking down
somebody that I'm helping to to learn
and grow um a little bit so that it
stings not not too much but so that it
stings enough for them to realize damn
you know what you're right I could have
got my answer this
myself I need to do that you need to do
that because people have become
particularly entitled people people who
have a lot of money uh I don't it's not
just rich people hate that's not what
I'm doing but I have dealt with people
who have come to me and like you're the
teacher you're supposed to know tell me
what I'm supposed to know I like you can
figure this out have you even attempted
to figure it out on your own well no
because I don't know how yeah but how
are you g to find out how well you're
the teacher you're supposed to tell me
that kind of attitude does not fly in it
or science the idea that you cannot
learn for
yourself it's just unsustainable it's
completely unsustainable so you need to
train yourself to be able to get that
answer and by the way the next time
somebody comes to you about this you
don't need to be sorry for my bad
language a dick about it but and I have
been I definitely
I I I got a reputation on Twitch as
being just an [__] because random
twitch people who are so full of
dopamine addiction and instant
gratification they would come into this
is a true story they would come into my
streams they still do it to this day
there is big white letters on the top of
the screen that tell my location on the
bike down to the city the exact
temperature and everything and you know
what they ask me in the chat
where is he where is he writing does
somebody know where he is and then my
mods are like please look in the upper
left corner of the screen and they're
like
oh I'm not kidding that is like that is
like the epitome of the opposite of
autodidactic thinking not even spending
a second to think about how could I
answer this question for myself right
and I'm telling you right now
whether or not you get smacked down and
sent to let me Google that for you which
is hilarious by the way you can if
somebody posts a thing you can go to let
me Google that for you and put the
question and then send it to them as the
answer and it will actually animate them
using Google to get their own answer
somebody was too lazy to Google it for
themselves um
so so don't be the person who's too lazy
be the don't be the person who who goes
you know walks across the you know the
entire building in some cases just to
ask you a stupid question that they
could have researched on their own or
that they could have figured out don't
don't be that person but and and
understand that those persons exist um
and then we'll end on the happy note so
let me tell you a story about one of the
most intelligent most dedicated
autodidacts I have ever known I happen
to marry her in fact I think that it
might be that she is such an
autodidactic human being that I have
come to just really appreciate her at a
core level and there's something to be
said about this so my wife is an artist
and my wife my wife's brain is not in
one category she she does sculpture she
does fine art she's been called the
greatest figure drawer and drawing
drawing artist in our region by another
highly acclaimed artist she's extremely
talented she's just she's in her third
book she's got she's got art in Austria
showing she had her own gallery show
with the ambassador to Germany or the
German ambassador to America attending I
mean she she's the real deal and and I
really appreciate art I'm I I like to do
graphic art things like that myself but
but something about artists that they
have figured out and this is where the
the the clicking clicking in connection
between creativity and autodidactic
nature comes in right because science at
it's at the core is a creative Pursuit
as well because the formulation of a
hypothesis a theory um and and you know
the execution and the imagination and
the visualization of that thing those
are all highly creative processes and as
we all know most people who pursue art
as a career they are already highly
creative and so they learned you know my
wife is particularly good at that
because she's regularly mixing she's not
a mixed media artist but she's regularly
mixing influences from one area into
another one so she's seeing you know
she's doing something with print making
and and line cut and stuff and she sees
that she can add that an element of
sculpture to it or something and she
just regularly finds Well so here's the
best part of the story so she was making
a piece where it was a it was a
sculpture of a bunny and it was like
supposed to be um all messed up and
stuff and when you touched it she wanted
it to say something so my wife said
about learning cprogramming
for her
self on her own in her own way and she
she coded the hardware
device uh to play upon un touching it
and everything it was it was uh ended up
being an uino and I the details are
irrelevant but she she took it on and it
was so funny because I remember um her
going through it and she's like man some
of these YouTube tutorials on see are
really bad and I'm like you think
and so but I mean so here's this artist
you know who took it upon herself to
teach herself see I mean she learned it
so well that she was actually able to
use her thing to do a demonstration to a
class that I was having where um uh she
and and and her her partner in crime was
working on it they actually had
alligator clips tied to a piece of of
aluminum foil and and they had written
this code that changed the frequency
coming through the speaker so that these
kids could like you know play different
things by just moving their finger on on
the aluminum foil and and she learned
all of that herself she learned the
electronics herself she learned the
coding part herself she made the
sculpture herself you know to contain
the thing and I am just blown away to to
this day I am blown away by my wife and
as busy as we are and and all the things
that might happened to somebody who's
been married for you know almost 10 more
than 10 years um you know we I always
have that and and I one of the things
about her that I really love is that
she's just so completely totally
autodidactic by about how she approaches
everything and we'll sit there and Sip
Coffee and we'll complain about all the
people in the world who are not
autodidactic we try not to be too
negative but we're like yeah can you
imagine not being able to answer your
own questions can you imagine having to
like depend on someone else to teach you
something oh it must be so exhausting s